What?
怎麼了？
Just as I thought.
果然是這樣
When you alter the past, it changes the future,
過去的歷史若遭塗改 未來也會因此改變
creating a time paradox.
那便是所謂的時間悖論
What is it?
發生什麼事了？
What's the matter?
怎麼了？小渚
Do you want me to touch you, Nagisa?
你是要我摸你嗎？小渚
When a time paradox occurs…
一旦發生時間悖論…
You feel a tingling.
你會有一陣霹靂啪啦的感覺
It really is, isn't it?
果然沒錯
It has to be.
事情一定就是這樣
Are you sure?
你確定嗎？
A time paradox.
時間悖論
What do you want?
你到底要不要我摸？
What are these two doing?
這兩個人在做什麼啊？
Good question.
我也想知道
ICHIRO OGAWA DRIVER'S LICENSE, VALID UNTIL SHOWA 64
（小川市郎 駕照）
Thank you for your patience. My name is Wakai.
久等了，敝姓若井
-I will guide you through the process. -Right.
-由我負責辦理您的手續 -好的
Were you okay with the standard plan?
關於費用選標準方案 有合您的心意嗎？
"Were"?
“有合您的心意”？
Did you prefer the unlimited calls and data bargain plan?
無線通話跟上網吃到飽的優惠方案 有合您的心意嗎？
Calls? Data?
“通話”？“上網”？
"Did"?
“有合您的心意”？
If you get hung up on her grammar, we can't move forward.
你如果一直糾結在那句 就會談不下去啦
Why the past tense?
她為什麼要用過去式？
Hey!
喂！
Is it because I'm from the past?
是因為我是從過去來的嗎？
Are Mr. Ogawa and I not allowed to be together?
我跟小川先生不能在一起嗎？
Mr. Ogawa is my junior high school homeroom teacher.
小川老師可是我國中時的班導喔
I mean, he was born in Showa 10.
他是昭和10年出生的
He'd be 88 now, since he's the same age as me.
也就是88歲的米壽呢 因為他和我同齡
Here you go.
來
Enjoy.
請慢用
Thank you.
謝謝你
What's with Wakai?!
那個若井是怎樣？
Treating me like an old man, when she's not young either!
她也老大不小了，還把我當老人看！
We couldn't change ownership without parental permission.
果然沒辦法轉移門號 需要家長的同意
Mr. Ogawa!
小川老師！
Huh? Who the hell are you?
什麼？你是誰？
It's Inoue!
我是井上！
Student number 2, Class B, Grade 2 at School 6.
葛飾區立第六國中2年B班座號二號
I'm Masakazu Inoue!
井上昌和！
It's been so long, Mr. Ogawa!
好久不見，老師！
-Yeah, yeah. -I've been wanting to see you!
-好啦… -我好想你喔，老師！
Sure.
你好…
It takes me back.
真是令人懷念啊
You haven't changed at all.
你完全沒變耶
I'm so glad I got to see you!
能見到你，我超開心的！
You don't seem excited.
你也太冷淡了吧
I mean, it's revolting.
因為你很肉麻啊
Even if you think so, don't say it.
那種事就算在心裡想，也不能說出來
Have you forgotten
你忘記了嗎？
the promise we made 38 years ago?
我們在38年前曾做過約定啊
Look.
你看這個
Hey, four-eyes.
喂，眼鏡仔
Can a time machine be built?
時光機是做得出來的嗎？
Yes.
我認為可以
Remember?
“我認為可以”
Oh, right.
對了，我想起來了
At the essay presentation.
-是作文課對吧？ -對
I suppose it happened.
確實有這回事
You suppose?
“有這回事”？
I believed your words, that's why I spent 38 years--
我可是對老師的話深信不疑 耗費38年…
It's hard to grasp, okay?
我又不這麼覺得
For me, it was just a few weeks ago.
對我來說只是兩、三週前的事
It's not like "You haven't changed at all!"
跟我說“你完全沒變耶” 我也無法產生共鳴
For me, you've changed so much, it's scary.
我反而覺得你變化大得讓人害怕
What's with that haircut?
那是什麼髮型啊？
You look like a convict.
你是囚犯嗎？
I kept this haircut for 38 years so you'd recognize me instantly.
為了讓你可以立刻回想起來 38年來我都沒換過髮型喔
Typical of you to do that, Inoue.
還真像是你會做的事情，井上
And I'm the one who's traveled through time.
不過反而是我到未來了，對吧？
Damn it!
可惡！
I've wasted 38 years of my life!
那我的38年究竟有什麼意義啊？
Oh, this smartphone.
話說這手機
It's your son's, right?
是你兒子的吧？
Right!
對耶！
Inoue, come with us.
井上，你陪我去個地方
-Come on! -O-Okay…
-快過來！ -好啦…
So you want to transfer ownership of the smartphone
那麼以井上昌和先生名義簽約的
from Mr. Masakazu Inoue's son
令郎的手機
to Mr. Akitsu, and this grandfather…
將轉到秋津先生的名下，並給爺爺…
I'm not a grandfather.
我才不是爺爺
Pardon me.
失禮了
So, Mr. Ichiro Ogawa will be using this phone.
由小川市郎先生接手使用
You got that right.
有合我的心意喔
I will handle the process now.
那我這就去辦理手續
-Just a moment, please. -Sure.
-請稍等一下 -好
Inoue, brighten the screen.
井上，幫我把畫面調亮
You hold down this button.
要先長按這個鍵
So, the other side of this wall…
這面牆的另一邊…
is Showa?
就是昭和年代？
You were covering the hole with a poster, right?
你曾用海報把洞蓋起來對吧？
I don't remember.
我不記得了
You were! Pull yourself together, old man!
就是那樣沒錯！ 老頭子，給我振作一點！
The other side had Kyon Kyon's "Nagisa no Haikara Ningyo" poster
對面是Kyon Kyon的 《沙灘上的摩登人魚》海報
and this side had her 40th anniversary poster.
這邊則是Kyon Kyon的40週年海報
He fell from the ceiling the second time.
他說第二次是從上面掉下來的
Ow!
好痛！
What year is it?
現在是哪一年？
Showa 61.
昭和61年
Now that you mention it,
聽你這麼一說
something like that
就覺得好像有發生過
might have happened.
那種事呢
This is a time paradox.
這就是時間悖論
Since you altered the barkeep's past, his memory has also changed.
因為更動了老闆的過去 他的記憶也跟著改變了
Well, he didn't remember much to begin with.
不過他本來就是個健忘的人
Anyway, why do I go to the future by bus but come back through the toilet?
話說回來，為什麼去程是公車 回程卻每次都要通過廁所？
That's because…
是因為啊…
I don't know.
我也不曉得
You don't know?
你不曉得啊？
Let's go.
我們走吧
It's still a work in progress!
因為現在才開發到一半嘛！
And you said you go to the future by bus,
還有啊，雖然你說去程是公車
but the way I invented it, you travel from the present to the past.
但就開發者的角度來看 從現代回到過去才是去程
You just happened to hop on the return bus.
老師是擅自坐上了回程的公車才對
Hey, Nagisacchi.
我說小渚啊
Will you add me as a friend and connect with me?
要來加好友嗎？要搭上線嗎？
Will you scan the QR code?
要顯示QR碼？要掃一下嗎？
Right.
好啦…
-Here. -Okay.
-來吧 -好
There.
好了
That's me.
那就是我
Tap the round photo to go to the registration screen.
只要碰圓形照片 就會跳到加好友的頁面
You sure know a lot.
你還真懂
My company made this app.
因為這是我們公司開發的應用程式
The two of you made contact in the elevator.
你們兩個在電梯裡互相碰觸時…
-It works! -Then, you felt a zapping. That means…
-成功了耶！ -既然發生觸電般的情況，就表示…
NAGISACCHI, YOU'RE LOOKING CUTE
（小渚，你今天也好可愛喔）
It's marked as read!
出現“已讀”字樣了！
That means you were about to cross a line you shouldn't cross!
你們當時想做的事是絕對不能做的！
What about this?
那這樣呢？
LET'S GO EAT GRILLED MEAT?
（要不要去吃燒肉？）
READ
（已讀）
It's marked as read!
已讀了…
Can't you do that later?
你能不能晚點再玩手機啊？
Toson Shimazaki intentionally wrote it this way
在這個部分島崎藤村
to express the moment of falling in love.
表現的是開始談戀愛時的心動感覺
The feeling of meeting a beautiful girl.
代表遇見美麗少女時的心情
Do you understand?
你們懂嗎？
HOW DO YOU FEEL ABOUT SHIZUKA?
（你對靜香有何想法？）
And this "pale crimson fall fruit" is…
再來是這裡 “淡紅的秋季果實”是指…
What does the apple represent?
而為何會出現蘋果呢？
Who knows the answer?
有人知道原因嗎？
Me!
我知道…
LIKE=YES DISLIKE=NO CIRCLE ONE!
（喜歡選“是”，討厭選“否” 擇一圈選）
Huh?
什麼？
What?!
怎麼回事？
Sakisaka, be quiet!
向坂，給我安靜一點！
Sorry.
抱歉
All right, anyone else?
其他的同學有人知道嗎？
Me!
我知道！
I think the sweet and sour taste of apples resembles the image of first love.
蘋果酸酸甜甜的滋味 跟初戀的感覺很像
That's right.
完全正確
DID YOU WATCH YORU HIT LAST NIGHT?
（有看昨天的《夜之金曲》？）
He mentioned the apple's flavor.
他想表現初戀的酸甜
"Yoru Hit"?
“《夜之金曲》”？
It hinted at the taste of first love.
透過與酸甜蘋果的關聯性
It's rhetoric that expresses the author's feelings.
讓作者陷入戀愛的心情更容易被理解
And there's another keyword.
還有另一個關鍵字
YELL WAAH! AT NOON SHARP
（十二點一到就大喊“哇！”）
This is…
這就代表…
not yet…
尚未…
This started…
才剛開始…
You startled me!
嚇死我了！
You little punks!
你們搞什麼啊？真是的！
What the hell?
還說我丟人？
You weren't listening at all, were you?
你們根本沒在聽課嘛！
What's so fun about being with girls?
臭女生，這有什麼好開心的？
They're fun.
很開心啊
They comment on your Stories and sometimes send you DMs.
就像大家在限時動態留言 但偶爾也會有人傳私訊過來
Sorry.
抱歉啦
I guess you wouldn't know.
你聽不懂吧？
"Kiyoshi, it looks like you're Shizuka's type."
“清同學，你好像是 靜香喜歡的類型呢
"If you're single, answer yes."
如果你沒有交往對象就回‘是’
"If not, answer no."
有對象就回‘否’
"If baseball is your love, answer Bass."
如果你把棒球當成戀人 就回‘巴斯’”
You only have three options: yes, no, and Bass!
叫你“是、否、巴斯”三選一啊！
Girls are so stupid.
女生真是無聊透頂
And yet, you're reading a shojo manga.
你嘴上這麼說，卻在讀少女漫畫
I understand Gilbert so well it hurts.
吉爾貝爾的孤獨是我的切身之痛
THE SONG OF WIND AND TREES
（《風與木之詩》）
What? The Song of Wind and Trees
什麼？《風與木之詩》
is a BL manga classic.
可是BL漫畫的經典之作耶
What's BL?
“BL”？
A bacon and lettuce manga?
“培根生菜漫畫”的簡稱？
He said he could only love men.
他說自己只愛得了男人
Huh?
胡說什麼？
Wait a minute. Inoue said that?
等一下，這是井上說的？
I know PL, though.
如果是PL我就知道喔
It's where Kiyohara and Kuwata…
有清原、桑田…
BL stands for Boys' Love.
“BL”指的是男性之間的戀愛
Kuwata and Kiyohara?
你說桑田跟清原是那種關係？
Junko, it's only eight.
純子，現在才八點
Go for a ride on someone's bike. You're a hussy, aren't you?
你就坐某人的機車出去玩吧 反正你是個女流氓
That's a rude way to shoo me out.
你趕我走的方法也太隨便了吧
Sorry.
對不起…
This is your home, isn't it?
這裡畢竟是你家嘛
And?
然後呢？
He went on to confess his love.
我順勢被告白了
To you?
被井上告白？
Kiyoshi, I'm in love with you!
阿清！我喜歡你！
Since I met you, you've never felt like a stranger.
打從第一次見面我就覺得你不是外人
Answer me with yes, no, or Bass!
“是、否、巴斯”，擇一回答我吧！
No, he's just confused.
不對，那絕對是他誤會了
He only said that because girls aren't into him.
他只是因為絲毫沒有女人緣 才失去理智亂說話
How do you know that?
你幹嘛擅自下定論？
True.
的確如此
Why are you getting so worked up about Inoue?
為什麼只要扯到井上 你總是這麼激動？
Why?
問我原因？
Because he's my future husband and the father of Kiyoshi.
因為他將來會成為我的丈夫 也是阿清的父親
Inoue is right about Kiyoshi not feeling like a stranger.
所以井上只有 覺得兒子不像外人這件事說對了
Anyway, your answer should be no.
話說回來，你要回答“否”吧
We're a thing, aren't we?
我們不是在交往嗎？
How would I know?
我不確定啊
You don't let me see your boobs.
你又不讓我看你的胸部
And you told Mutchy you weren't dating me.
在阿睦學長面前 你也說過我們沒在交往
And?
然後呢？
I decided to date him for a bit.
我決定試著跟他交往看看
-What?
-什麼？
You two-timer!
你竟敢劈腿！
-Be quiet! -Two-timer!
-給我閉嘴… -劈腿…
Do you even understand?
你知道自己處在什麼情況下嗎？
LGBTQ, right?
就是LGBTQ吧？
There was a gay kid in my previous junior high as well.
之前上的國中 也有喜歡同性的男學生啊
I see.
是這樣啊
I didn't know.
我都不知道
He said he had a crush on me, so we dated for a bit.
我被他告白，也稍微交往過
We only held hands as we walked home, though.
雖然只是回家路上牽牽手而已
Gross!
讓人不舒服！
What's with your reaction?
這是什麼反應？
You always say it's not right to discriminate based on sexuality.
你不是老是說不能性別歧視嗎？
You're right.
沒錯
It's not right to discriminate.
歧視是不對的喔
Diverse sexuality should be equally recognized.
要平等地對待多元性別才行
I don't even know if I really like girls.
再說我也不確定 自己是不是真的喜歡女生
Ugh!
討厭啦！
I can't believe you!
你竟然有臉說出那種話！
I mean, I like boobs!
我是喜歡胸部沒錯！
But maybe that's all I like.
不過也可能只是喜歡胸部而已啊
That's not how it works.
才沒有那種人咧
Anyway, that's not the issue.
而且問題不在這裡
It's about time you realized, my son!
再說你好歹該察覺吧，兒子
His name, his buzz cut, his obsession with time machines,
他不只跟你父親同名同姓 還都是平頭，也一樣喜歡時光機
are all clear indicators!
明明伏筆多到爆！
And?
結果呢？
We went along with the flow and decided to try kissing.
自然而然就說要不要接吻看看
What kind of flow is that?
哪裡自然而然了？
You're the worst!
太差勁了！
You haven't even kissed me yet!
我們明明還沒親過！
You jerk!
你這個笨蛋！
A time paradox!
是時間悖論！
That's when I realized.
然後我就領悟到
I actually really like boobs!
我果然最愛胸部了！
No, Kiyoshi, that's not it.
不對，重點不是那個，阿清！
No, I mean,
說錯了
I really like you, Junko!
我果然喜歡純子學姐
Are you kidding me?
什麼跟什麼？
So you only like me for my boobs?
說得你好像只喜歡我的胸部
Screw you!
少開玩笑了，笨蛋！
Junko, calm down!
純子，你冷靜點！
Hello?
誰啦？
Inoue?
井上嗎？
Quit putting weird thoughts into Kiyoshi's head!
你這小子不要亂教 阿清莫名其妙的事啦！
Move.
給我聽一下
Inoue, listen to me carefully.
井上同學，你認真聽我說
You look down on girls because you're not popular with them.
你只是因為自己 完全不受歡迎才瞧不起女生
That's misogyny.
就只會鄙視女性
You've always had this tendency.
你從以前就是這樣
There's always been a misogynistic aspect to you.
有厭女的特質，這點從以前就沒變過
It's always guys like you who mistake homosocial relationships
就是你這種男人 會把同性友愛跟同性愛混為一談
as homosexual and seek solace in homosexuality.
希望在同性愛中得到救贖
That's where you are now!
這是你目前的心理狀態！
Do you see? You're going after guys because girls aren't into you!
你懂嗎？只是因為 不受女生歡迎，才找上男生！
You have second-grade syndrome!
你是得了中二病嗎？
Unless you let go of the notion that girls are to blame for your lack of popularity,
如果你不捨棄自己不受歡迎 都該怪女生的這種想法
you'll stay unchanged and unpopular. Got that?
就不會有人喜歡你 也無法改變，有沒有聽懂？
Just because girls--
就因為不受女生歡迎…
Second-grade syndrome?
說什麼中二病啊？
I'll be in third grade this spring!
我春天就要升三年級了啦！
Oops, I sent it.
送出去了
Mr. Ogawa.
小川先生
This is my colleague and a drama producer.
他是跟我同時進公司的連續劇製作人
I'm Sekine.
敝姓關根
Right. What's the matter?
好，有什麼事嗎？
We've got a complaint about the title of a drama starting in April.
4月檔期的連續劇名收到投訴
This teen drama, Cheerleading Boys,
這部《老子們的啦啦隊》
follows students from a boys' school as they attempt cheerleading.
是個描寫男高中生 挑戰成為啦啦隊的青春連續劇
But we received a comment stating the term "boys"
但“老子們”這個詞
is homosocial, making girls feel excluded.
含有同性友愛的意義 有人批評這把女性排除在外了
Who wrote this? A homo?
是誰寫的？同志寫的嗎？
Huh?
什麼？
There you go again.
你又來了
You're as sharp as ever, Mr. Ogawa.
真是愛說笑啊，小川先生
You find it funny when guys spread their legs
你們就是覺得 男生混入女生中張開雙腿
and prance around like girls, right?
在那邊飛來跳去的很有趣對吧？
Own it.
有自信一點嘛
When we make one's sex the primary focus,
最近如果太強調性別
we tend to receive complaints saying it goes against gender equality.
就會因為不合乎性別平等而遭到抗議
From who?
會被誰抗議？
From "Gender"?
被“幸別”抗議？
There's no one by the name of gender.
是沒有叫做“幸別”的人物存在啦
Then, what about Kensaku Morita's I'm a Man!?
那森田健作的《女校男生》呢？
That won't do. It's out of the question.
不行，明顯出局了
What about The Woman of S.R.I.?
那《科搜研之女》呢？
If Ms. Yasuko Sawaguchi has reservations about it, then it's a no.
如果澤口靖子小姐 覺得心裡不舒服就不行
What about Seven Men and Women, Summer Story?
《男女7人夏物語》呢？
That's fine, right?
算過關吧？
But it says men and women.
但這也把“男女”說出來了啊
Seven Humans, Summer Story, then?
如果是《人類7人夏物語》就行？
Yes. It sounds boring, though.
確實就沒問題了 不過一點都不吸引人
Basically, titles like Cheerleading Boys and Girls
所以說得極端一點 像是《男女都是啦啦隊》
or Human Cheerleaders won't make anyone feel excluded.
或是《人類啦啦隊》 就不會排除任何人了
Oh, please. That's just weird.
拜託，聽起來也太奇怪了吧
And Marketing wants a title that can be shortened to four characters.
另外宣傳部門說 希望片名也能精簡成四個字
Huh?
什麼？
It makes hashtag searches easier.
這樣用主題標籤比較容易搜尋
H-hash?
標什麼？
For instance, An Incurable Case of Love could be shortened to ICOL.
《戀愛可以持續到天長地久》 簡略成《戀愛持續》，就像這樣子
It's similar to how Kato-chan Ken-chan Gokigen TV
就像是把《加藤茶志村健搞笑電視》
is shortened to KCKC.
簡稱為《加藤志村》這樣？
Sorry, I'm taking a break.
不好意思，先休息一下
Give him my chat ID, will you?
對了，把我的聊天室帳號給他
I'll reach out once I've come up with a good title.
我如果有好點子會再跟他聯絡
Wakai, can I have a moment?
若井妹妹，可以問個問題嗎？
I'm sorry, please issue a numbered ticket.
不好意思，請先抽號碼牌
I have to?
得這樣做啊？
Even though we know each other?
我們又不是不認識
Coming through.
借過
TICKET 1
（一號號碼牌）
Ticket number 1…
一號的客人…
Me!
就是我！
Wakai, what's a hashtag?
若井妹妹 “主題標籤”是什麼東西？
It's the # symbol placed in front of a word you want to search.
就是在想搜尋的詞前面加上記號#
This one that looks like the first character in "well"?
就是這個長得像“井”的啊？
I see. Thanks, Wakai.
原來如此，謝謝你喔，若井妹妹
Waka-hashtag.
若“主題標籤”妹妹
Ticket number 2, please.
號碼牌二號的客人
There are transitive and intransitive verbs.
動詞分為他動詞以及自動詞
Transitive verbs are those
他動詞是“將某物怎麼樣”
that require an object…
會需要有進行動作的對象
MEET ME AT SCANDAL AFTER SCHOOL
（放學後我在緋聞等你）
Like "know" and "see." These are transitive verbs.
像是“得知”、“看”這類的動詞 就屬於他動詞
Here you go.
讓你久等了
-Thanks. -Thank you.
-謝謝 -謝謝你
Since then, I've been pondering it this whole time,
從那之後我就一直在思考
but nothing is coming to mind.
但是毫無頭緒
Do you have family, Ms. Inushima?
犬島小姐有家人嗎？
I've divorced my husband
我與丈夫離婚了
and am now living with my 18-month-old son and my father.
目前跟一歲半的兒子還有父親一起住
Mr. Ogawa also lost his wife early on
小川老師的妻子也很早就過世了
and became a single father.
是個單親爸爸
Are you seeing him lately?
你最近有見到老師嗎？
I'm trying not to see him.
我有盡量不跟他見面
He seems to interpret the zapping as a sign we're meant for each other
他倒是因為之前的觸電感 覺得我是他命中註定的對象
and is texting me nonstop.
一直狂傳訊息給我
Hello?
喂？
Kiyoshi?
你說阿清？
No, not yet.
他還沒回來喔
I wonder if he's forgotten.
那傢伙是不是忘記了啊？
He asked me to help him buy a reference book after school.
他之前要我放學後陪他去買參考書
Yeah.
好
I'll wait a little longer.
那我再等一下
Sorry. If he calls, I'll let him know.
抱歉啊，如果他有打回來我再跟他說
Mr. Ogawa.
小川先生
Mr. Ogawa?
小川先生？
Nagisacchi!
小渚！
Did you see what I sent you?
你看了嗎？我剛才傳給你了
A photo of a naughty-looking cloud!
是形狀有點色的雲朵照片喔！
This is Premium Saturday's…
這位是《優質星期六》的…
I'm Kurita.
敝姓栗田
Thank you for your help during the Yashima incident.
八嶋事件時受你關照了
Want to add me as a friend already?
我們趕緊來加好友吧
I'll invite you to the program's group chat.
那我會邀請你加入節目的群組
I'm not sure if…
不太合適吧
Yay!
好耶！
So? What is it?
那你今天來有什麼事？
We're collecting oldie songs from our dads' era for a feature,
我目前正為了特別節目 在搜集父親世代的懷舊歌曲
but all the lyrics are problematic in terms of compliance.
但大部分的歌詞都不符合規範
What?
你說什麼？
"HOTEL" YUTAKA SHIMAZU
（《酒店》 島津豐）
Okay, stop.
停，確定不行！
Let him get to the hotel part, at least.
至少讓他唱酒店那段嘛！
No letters or calls allowed? That's moral harassment.
寫信跟打電話都不行 這已經是精神霸凌了
Not cool. So not cool.
不行，這我絕對無法接受
You too, Wakai?
怎麼連若井妹妹都這樣說？
In the second verse, the woman visits her affair partner's house on a Sunday.
而且在第二段裡 出軌對象會在週日跑去看男人的家
It's about an affair between a harassing man and a stalking girl.
根本是精神霸凌男 和跟蹤狂女的出軌之歌嘛
Not cool.
完全無法接受…
"CASABLANCA DANDY" KENJI SAWADA
（“Casablanca Dandy” 澤田研二）
Okay, stop.
停，這也不行
It's not just power harassment, it's DV!
這是暴力騷擾，根本是家暴！
Not cool.
絕對不行…
I cringed singing it myself.
我一邊唱也一邊覺得不可行
Many songs by men tend to belittle women.
許多男性歌手的歌都很鄙視女性呢
How about a song from a female perspective?
那我們試著加入 女性觀點的歌曲如何？
Who ordered the Napolitan dish?
拿坡里義大利麵是哪位點的？
That would be me.
-是我的 -來
Kiyoshi, are you together with Junko?
清同學在跟純子學姐交往嗎？
They're cohabiting.
他們在同居
Hey!
別亂說話啦！
We're living together due to family circumstances.
因為家庭因素所以住在一起
I bet she walks around in a towel after a bath,
她洗完澡後 會裹著一條浴巾在家裡亂晃
and it excites you, doesn't it?
然後你會為此小鹿亂撞吧？
I'm not interested.
我對那種事又沒興趣
You're getting red!
你都變紅了！
I am not!
才沒有！
You totally are!
明明就有！
Where?
哪裡？
Your nose.
鼻子
My nose? No way.
鼻子？別亂講啦
I just like the color red.
我只是單純喜歡紅色
I'll turn toward you!
我會回頭！
If you said that to me, I'd turn twice and end up where I started.
如果小渚這樣對我說 我會回頭兩次，結果回到原位
What's the matter, Team White?
你們是怎樣啊？白組
Isn't it kind of intense?
不覺得沉重嗎？
Agreed.
很沉重
Most songs from Team Red are intense.
紅組確實大多很沉重
We need to reconsider the red-and-white format as well.
紅組、白組的分類也應該要重新審視
Huh? Why?
什麼？為何啊？
For diversity.
因為多樣性
It's an era of gender neutrality.
這是性別中立的時代
Some people don't identify with red or white.
也得顧慮不屬於紅或白的人
There's that word again, "gender."
又出現了，“幸別”
We're fans of Kyon Kyon because we love her.
我們是因為喜歡Kyon Kyon 才會想支持她
Not because she's a woman.
可不是因為她是女的
If not by sex, do we use income levels to divide the performers?
如果不能用男女，那要用什麼分？ 貧富差距嗎？
Rich vs. Poor Song Battle?
難道要改成《富窮歌唱大賽》？
How about Jomon vs. Yayoi people?
《繩文人彌生人歌唱大賽》呢？
Did you know? Wet earwax indicates Jomon ancestry,
你知道嗎？耳屎比較黏的是繩文人
while dry indicates Yayoi ancestry.
比較乾的是彌生人喔
I'd hate a song battle like that.
我才不想看那種歌唱對決
Hey, how about something more lighthearted?
我說啊，差不多想來點輕鬆的了吧？
Nagisacchi, sing an Onyanko song.
小渚，來唱小貓的歌吧
Outrageous!
真是引人遐想！
Akimoto sure has a screw loose!
不愧是秋元，太有才華了！
I don't even feel like mentioning compliance.
這內容我連有沒有合規範都懶得提
I've had enough. I'm leaving.
受不了，我要回去了
What's more, Akimoto is still churning out hits.
而且秋元先生 到現在都還是金曲製作人耶
He is?!
真的嗎？
He'll go to hell!
他這樣可是會下地獄的！
"HIGHTEEN BOOGIE" MASAHIKO KONDO
（“Highteen Boogie” 近藤真彥）
I'm taking this one.
這是我點的
It's my dad's favorite.
這是我爸的拿手歌
What's the matter, Junko?
怎麼了？純子
Nothing.
沒什麼
I just wanted to get a ride on someone's bike.
我只是想坐著某人的機車 到處晃晃罷了
Stupid girl.
你這笨蛋
Why'd you do that?
你做什麼？
Hey, you mantis!
喂，你這個像螳螂的混帳！
Tell me your dad's name.
告訴我你老爸叫什麼名字
My dad?
你說我爸？
It's Mutsumi.
他叫睦實
Mutsumi Akitsu.
秋津睦實
I knew it.
果然沒錯
It's Mutchy!
就是那個阿睦學長！
Akitsu, you're Mutchy's son, aren't you?
秋津，你是阿睦的兒子嗎？
You know his father?
你認識他的爸爸？
Do I know him?
別說什麼認識了
He's a biker gang member in Katsushika who's seducing my daughter!
他是正在拼命誘惑我女兒的 葛飾區暴走族
For real?
真的假的？
I remember him!
我想起來了！
His family owned a dumpling shop.
我記得他老家是賣糰子的
He adored Matchy and insisted on being called Mutchy.
他因為崇拜阿真先生 所以要大家叫他“阿睦”
Otherwise, he'd threaten us with a belt. He's legendary.
不照做就會被他用腰帶抽打 是傳說中的學長
That's so lame of him.
老爸也太土了吧
By the way, my name
順帶一提，我的名字是…
is Masahiko.
真彥
That means…
也就是說…
Akitsu,
秋津
is your mother…
你的母親該不會是…
No, don't tell me!
等一下，不准說！
You bastard!
你這個混蛋！
If you dare mention Junko's name,
如果你那張嘴巴敢講出純子的名字
I will stab you to death!
我就要把你刺死！
A muddler won't work.
用攪拌棒是刺不死的
I've got a counseling meeting!
有人預約諮詢！
I'll share my mom's name in the group chat.
我會把老媽的名字傳到群組聊天室
Don't you dare!
不要傳，你這笨蛋！
You can't share something so important via chat!
那麼重要的事 不能用聊天室說，蠢蛋！
Junko?
純子？
I'm back.
我回來了
Welcome back.
回來啦
It's suddenly raining.
忽然就下起雨了呢
Huh?
奇怪
Aren't you with Junko?
純子沒跟你在一起嗎？
You wanted to buy a reference book, right?
她說你們約好要去買參考書
You silly! Did you forget?
你這笨蛋，難道忘記了嗎？
Want to come over?
你要來我家嗎？
I'll lend you dry clothes.
我借你衣服換
What?
搞什麼？
Not you again.
怎麼又是你啊？
This is Katie Ikeda, an intimacy coordinator.
這位是親密行為協調員的 池田凱蒂小姐
Huh? What the hell is that?
什麼？我聽不懂啦
Sorry. I'm just so busy.
對不起，因為我太忙了
Take a seat.
坐下吧…
If there's anything I don't know, I Google it.
不懂的事，大叔我會上網查
Interior cootie-nator?
是叫“親米行為協跳員”是吧？
Say that again.
再說一次
"Specializes in choreographing intimate scenes, including sex scenes."
“親密戲或床戲的專門協調員”
I wouldn't have guessed.
你嗎？
You're a bit of a pervert, huh?
看不出來你這麼好色耶
Sorry. He means no offense.
對不起，他沒有惡意
Her role is to align the director's vision
她會將導演對於演出的期望
with the comfort level of the actors in advance to prevent any problems.
以及演員可以接受的上限事前協調好 以避免後續發生問題
Why can't they discuss it directly between themselves?
那種事情由當事人 直接討論不就好了？
Japanese people struggle with discussing sexual topics openly.
跟性有關的事情 日本人就是無法公開討論啊
It's hanky-panky. Just stick to the usual.
就是做那檔子事吧？ 表現出平常在做的樣子就好了啊
This sort of male-oriented mindset has hurt many women in the past.
那種男尊女卑的想法 讓多名女性在過去都受到了傷害
Sorry.
真是抱歉
They decided the title will be That Day's Dazzling You.
劇名已經決定了 是《給那天耀眼不已的你》
It's completely different from Cheerleading Boys.
你說《老子們的啦啦隊》嗎？ 完全變調了耶
-TDDY is a romantic drama and… -You've already shortened it.
-《那天耀眼》是臉紅心跳型連續劇 -已經在用簡稱了
There's a bit of an intimate scene in the fourth episode.
在第四集會有幾幕床戲
What?
什麼？
THE WAY OF MATCHY
（阿真之道）
Sit wherever you like.
看你要坐哪都行
All right.
好
Thanks.
謝謝
Get changed or you'll catch a cold.
快換衣服，不然會感冒
I don't know what happened.
我是不知道你碰到什麼事了
-But don't make your dad worry. -He's gone.
-但不能讓你爸擔心 -他又不在
Gone?
不在？
Where did he go?
他去哪了嗎？
No idea.
不知道
What about Kiyoshi?
阿清呢？
Nobody cares.
大家都不關心
Not about me.
不管我的事情
Nobody worries about me.
沒有任何人會擔心我
Everyone thinks I'm fine because I can take care of myself.
都認為“純子不要緊 因為她很堅強”
Give me a break.
開什麼玩笑？
I'm not doing all that because I want to.
我才不是因為想堅強才堅強的
I wish I could say "I don't want to touch fish."
“我不敢碰魚”
Or "I can't open a jar."
“我打不開瓶蓋” 這種話我也想說說看啊
But if I did, I wouldn't be able to cook.
不過那樣就無法做飯了
So I've been putting up with it all this time.
所以我才一路忍過來
But…
但是…
Kiyoshi's mother came and took over all the chores.
阿清的媽媽來到家後 會幫忙做所有家事
Then everyone started doing their own thing.
大家開始都只顧著自己
My dad went off somewhere.
老爸也不知道跑哪去了
Even Kiyoshi left.
阿清也一樣
He claimed to like me, but…
明明就說過他喜歡我
he's dating other girls and guys.
卻一下跟女生交往，一下跟男生交往
It's ticking me off.
我真的氣到不行
Nobody pays me any attention.
沒有一個人眼中有我
It's always going to be like that.
老是這樣
I'm going to be an old maid
我猜我會在沒人愛的情況下
without anyone paying attention to me.
漸漸變成大嬸
Mutchy?
學長？
Why are you naked?
你為什麼要光著身子？
I don't know.
我不知道
But
但是…
I care about you.
你對我來說很重要
So I won't leave you.
所以我無法丟著你不管
I only have eyes for you.
我眼中只有你
I'll protect you with my life.
我願意挺身保護你
I wanted to express
因為這份熾熱的心意
this passionate feeling.
我現在才會
That's why I'm naked.
與你坦誠相見
Thanks.
謝謝你
Want me to wear something?
我應該把衣服穿上嗎？
Whichever.
都可以
Come here, Junko.
過來這邊，純子
Cut!
卡！
Intimacy!
親密協調員！
At the audition, he said he'd let her do anything,
試鏡的時候明明說什麼都願意做
but now he's saying she has a pure and innocent image to maintain.
等真的被選上後 卻說藝人是清純派，不能露太多
Her cleavage can never be shown on camera.
胸口跟乳溝是絕對不能入鏡的！
-I'm counting on you, Intimacy. -Right.
-拜託你了，親密協調員 -好
Only her collarbone and above
上面最低只能露到鎖骨，下面…
and her ankles below.
只能拍腳踝以下
We can hardly show anything.
幾乎全都不能拍啊
How about we have her wear a turtleneck?
讓她換成高領的服裝如何？
Isn't this a sex scene?
這是床戲沒錯吧？
How about we wrap her in a sheet?
那用床單卷在她身上呢？
Let's give the impression while shooting only from the neck up.
就拍脖子以上，讓我看到床戲的氣氛
Stroke her hair--
撫摸她的頭髮…
He's going to touch her? No one told me this.
要摸她頭髮？這我可沒聽說
He won't.
那就不摸
How about he lifts her chin with his fingers?
不然用手指把她的下巴往上抬呢？
Fine.
就這麼辦吧
From the top!
那要再拍一次了喔！
-Okay.
-好的
"Don't say anything."
“什麼都不要說
"Your wet T-shirt
濕掉的T恤
is cute."
好可愛”
That's "Manatsu no Ichibyo"
《仲夏的一秒》
by Masahiko Kondo.
近藤真彥唱的
Damn it.
可惡
KIYOSHI, YOU JERK!
（阿清是大笨蛋！）
"The shirt on your naked skin. Sexy."
“裸身穿著T恤好性感
"It's a little wet. Sexy."
稍微濡濕，好性感”
"Jonetsu Neppu Serenade"
《熱情、熱風、小夜曲》
by Masahiko Kondo.
近藤真彥唱的
Matchy loves wet shirts.
阿真最喜歡濕掉的T恤了
This is embarrassing.
好害羞
Turn the light off.
把燈關掉
Cut!
卡！
You touched her!
你摸了她…
You touched her just now!
你剛才摸了她吧？
Managers aren't allowed to say cut!
不准由你這經紀人喊卡！
It's outside the frame.
那部分沒有入鏡
Then why did he have to touch her?
那就更沒必要摸了吧？
You're so fussy!
管這麼多，真的吵死了！
Fine. Lift your arms so you can't touch!
算了，為了不要摸到 你手舉高比萬歲姿勢！
How will they make sounds without touching?
明明沒被摸到，卻要她發出聲音？
With hand power!
這是手的力量！
Use hand power!
要使用手的力量！
Anyway, this girl became an actress because she wanted to act, right?
那女孩本來就是 因為想要演戲才來當演員的吧？
In that case, let her act!
那就全都要靠演技啊！
It's no different from eating scenes, fighting scenes,
像是吃飯或大亂鬥的戲碼
or dancing and singing scenes.
都跟唱歌、跳舞沒有差別啊
Why are intimate scenes treated differently?
為什麼只有親密戲是特例？
My favorite actresses, Mineko Nishikawa and Rino Katase
像是我喜歡的西川峰子還有片瀨梨乃
rose to fame through their bold stripping and explicit scenes.
她們都用大膽脫光 還有親身上陣的演技獲得了成功
Explicit scenes?
親身上陣？
That's right.
沒錯
That's how they made it.
直接勇敢親身上陣
They showed their tits and asses and committed!
把胸部跟屁股露出來熱情演出！
That's professionalism!
那才叫專業吧？
Who's this guy spouting nonsense?
這個從剛才就在吵的怪人到底是誰？
Huh?
你說什麼？
I'm this company's counselor.
我是敝公司的諮商師啦
Counselor? You?
諮商師？就這傢伙？
TV stations are messed up!
電視局也太誇張了吧！
Inoue!
井上！
What?
什麼事？
Do you know where Mutchy lives?
你知道阿睦學長的家在哪嗎？
It's the dumplings shop.
就是糰子店
Banzai
“萬歲
-Banzai -Stop.
-萬歲” -停下來
No more Matchy.
不要再提阿真的歌了
It overlapped a little.
有點擋到了
Twist her right leg counterclockwise.
把右腳往逆時針轉
Right leg, counterclockwise.
把右腳往逆時針轉一些
No. Her thigh will show.
不行，這樣會看到大腿！
Scratch that. Your thigh will show.
-會看到大腿，請先放下 -會看到啦
Twist her left leg clockwise and her hip counterclockwise.
那把左腳往順時針轉 腰部則逆時針轉
How about this?
這樣如何呢？
All the important parts are hidden.
這樣的話重點部位都遮得住
Who has sex in this position, though?
但沒人在床上會是這種姿勢吧？
It looks more like a judo technique.
看起來就像柔道的寢技
What is it, Intimacy?
怎麼了？親密協調員
She wants to experiment a little, so she'd like you to step out for a bit.
她說想照自己的想法演演看 請你先出去
What?
什麼？
Me?
我嗎？
It's my job as the intimacy coordinator to respect the actor's preferences.
尊重演員的意願 正是親密行為協調員的工作
AKITSU DUMPLINGS
（秋津糰子店）
Junko!
純子！
What's the matter?
怎麼了？
My stupid thing…
我這蠢下體…
won't ding-a-ling.
完全無法大放異彩
What?
什麼？
Sorry.
抱歉
Junko!
純子！
Is something the matter?
怎麼了？
Huh?
什麼？
No, it's nothing.
不，沒事
Junko!
純子！
Hey. Let go of me!
等等，放開我！
Just come with me!
總之跟我來！
Wow, I'm feeling super excited right now!
怎麼辦？我現在興奮到不行！
Why?
為什麼？
I managed to find you without a smartphone.
明明沒靠手機的力量，我卻找到你了
On a rainy night,
在下著雨的晚上
I managed to find you without using my phone.
我竟沒用智慧型手機 靠一己之力找到你
I'm amazing.
我好強啊
This is so cool!
太酷了！
I love Showa!
昭和棒透了！
Kiyoshi!
阿清！
If you're a man,
如果你是個男人
don't be an idiot and make the girl you love cry!
就別讓你愛的女人哭泣啊，笨蛋！
Mutchy!
學長！
Don't you ever let her go.
不准你再放開她的手
You got that?
聽懂了沒？
I won't.
聽懂了
Thanks, Junko.
謝謝你，純子
I'm sorry.
對不起
Nagisa, can I have a moment?
小渚，你現在有空嗎？
What is it?
怎麼了？
These ladies are,
她們幾個啊
how should I put it, members of…
雖然難以啟齒 不過都是小川先生的受害人團體
Victims?
受害人？
What's taking her so long to respond?
為什麼不立刻回覆？
-Sorry? -Mr. Ichiro, you can't cut in.
-什麼？ -市郎先生，得照順序才行啦
He's talking about a group chat.
他在說的是群組聊天室
I've been waiting ever since it was marked as read.
我看到已讀之後就一直在等
So why?
這是為什麼？
Last month, I got advice from Mr. Ogawa about my supervisor's power harassment.
之前我被主管職權騷擾，因此很煩惱 上個月找了小川先生商量
So I sent him a thank-you message, but…
然後我傳了道謝的訊息給他…
"Come talk to me whenever you want."
“隨時都能來找我商量喔”
"Thank you."
“謝謝你”
"How are things since then?"
“那之後如何了？
"Are you still being harassed?"
沒有再被職權騷擾了吧？
"My message is marked as read, but you haven't responded."
明明就已讀了卻不回覆”
"Bow."
“鞠躬”
"What's with the bow? Do you think this is funny?"
“鞠躬是什麼意思？你在搞笑嗎？
"Why did you delete your message?"
你剛才為什麼要收回訊息？
"Hey. Answer me!"
喂，給我回訊息”
This exchange itself is harassment.
那種訊息本身也構成騷擾
If we showed this to Personnel, he'd be fired on the spot.
這種聊天內容 如果被人事單位看到就完了
He also messaged our program's group chat.
他也有傳訊息到我們節目的群組
"Karaoke was a blast."
“之前卡拉OK唱得很開心呢
"By the way, how's the program coming along?"
話說節目後來做得如何了？”
I sent that on Friday night, and the show aired on Saturday.
我傳出訊息是在星期五晚上 節目是在星期六播出
And this is what I got today after all that silence!
從那天一直到今天 收到的訊息卻是這個
I mean, it didn't feel right for me to reply before you, the general director.
因為如果無視擔任總導播的栗田先生
I don't check my business phone on my days off,
我休假時不會去看公司的手機
so I only noticed on Monday.
到星期一才發現有訊息
AT LEAST LET ME KNOW HOW THE SHOW WENT
（好歹要報告一下節目成果吧！）
UNDERSTOOD
（明白了）
I get it. It's an understandable reaction.
確實會變成這樣呢
I always leave a program's group chat once the program is over.
我習慣在節目拍攝結束後就退出群組
You can get in touch if you're connected personally, after all.
畢竟如果有互加好友就能聯絡得上嘛
Leaving is cutting ties with the group.
退出群組就是表明要斷絕關係對吧？
It's like a breakup.
也就是絕交吧？
That's intense. You're taking this too seriously.
好有壓力啊 小川先生，你這樣讓人好有壓力
"Why did you leave the group?"
“為什麼退出群組了？
"What did I do?"
我做了什麼嗎？
"Give me your reason."
給我把理由說清楚”
That's intense!
好有壓力！
Feeling concerned, I decided to hear them out.
我因為擔心而想給意見
I created a new group and began chatting with them there.
就成立了新群組，跟大家聯絡
But then, someone invited Mr. Ogawa.
-卻有人邀請了小川先生 -什麼？
"So this is where you've been. I found you."
“原來你們在這裡，我終於找到了
"I want a drinking party on Thursday or Friday."
聚餐我希望排在星期四或星期五
"This place looks good."
這間店看起來不錯
"It has a Tabelog rating of 3.8 stars."
在美食評論網Tabelog上有3.8分”
-Scary.
-太可怕了 -好嚇人
What should we do?
怎麼辦？
I think someone should tell him.
我是覺得應該要告訴他啦
I might be responsible for this.
這可能是我的錯
In our group chat with the three of us,
三個人的群組聊天室
Nagisa has been ignoring your messages.
渚小姐一直都已讀不回耶
Ever since I shared my mom's name in the chat.
自從我把母親的名字傳上去後就這樣
About that.
關於那件事
I'm so glad it wasn't Junko.
幸好你媽不是純子，我真的放心了
But I've been checking my phone every minute, waiting for her to reply.
但我會想看小渚有沒有回訊息 一分鐘需要確認一次
It's making it hard to focus on work.
不然我就連工作都做不好
You have a smartphone addiction, like some high schooler.
你有嚴重的手機依賴症 通常是高中生會得的
When a message is read but not replied to,
明明已讀卻不回覆
to me, it feels like serving a meal without receiving a thank you!
就像是請人吃飯 對方卻沒說“謝謝招待”！
Damn it!
可惡，真是的！
Calm down
冷靜點
Mr. Ogawa
小川先生
Nagisacchi?
小渚？
Calm down, Mr. Ogawa
冷靜點，小川先生
It might be tough to grasp When you're new to it
你才剛開始接觸，雖然可能難以理解
But you can't take social media seriously
但社群媒體不是需要 如此認真投入的東西
You can't?
是這樣嗎？
When a message is marked as read, it means you've been heard.
而且“已讀”代表的就是 “我已經看過訊息了”
It's a response in itself.
已讀本身就是回覆
Marked as read means they're alive
已讀就能確認對方還活著
No reply is good news
沒有回覆就是好消息
Marked as read means they're well
已讀就代表對方身體無恙
It's silly to feel hurt
若因此感到孤獨就太蠢了
No!
不！
In that case…
如果是那樣的話…
Don't mark it as read
那不要標示已讀不就好了？
Marked as read makes me anxious
已讀後我會在意啊
No news is bad news
沒有回覆就是壞消息
Yeah, when your message is marked as read, you expect a reply,
的確如此，如果標示了已讀 就會希望得到回覆
putting pressure on the other person to respond.
也會覺得需要回覆對方吧？
And that's why…
結果得到的卻是…
Understood
明白了
No.
不
That's not it.
這樣不對啊
I'm not looking for a robotic response.
我想要的不是那種制式回覆
If I wanted a business interaction, I'd use a call network!
如果是業務聯絡的話 靠聯絡網就好了啊！
-A call network?
“聯絡網”？
They're not familiar with a call network
竟不知什麼是聯絡網！
Come on!
一起來！
Generation Z is missing out
就是這樣才受不了Z世代
They're not familiar with a call network
竟不知什麼是聯絡網！
Okay, thank you. Have a good day.
好的，謝謝，那我掛了
Call network…
聯絡網…
A calls B
A打給B
B calls C
B打給C
And on it goes
一個接一個打
Until Z calls A
最後Z再打回去給A
Hello?
喂？
This is Sakisaka.
我是向坂
Tomorrow's PTA meeting starts at 2 p.m.
明天的家長教師聯誼會是兩點開始
By the way, Intimacy,
我順便說一下，親密協調員
on the main actor's birthday,
在主角演員生日的時候
you were the only one who didn't send a birthday message!
只有你沒有在群組裡送上祝福！
That bothered me.
我覺得那樣不太好耶
You don't understand anything
你什麼都不懂
Wishing someone a happy birthday In a group chat
群組聊天室裡的“生日快樂”
Is nothing more than a public display
只不過是在作秀罷了
Really?
真的嗎？
If you truly want to celebrate someone, you message them in person.
如果是真心想祝福的對象 會直接傳訊息給對方
Calm down, Mr. Ogawa
冷靜點，小川先生
Everyone is vaguely aware
大家都隱約察覺到了
That social media isn't the place
所謂的社群媒體
For serious discourse
不是需要如此認真對談的場所
If you took everything seriously It would exhaust you
若每件事都這麼在意的話會很累喔
Is that how it is?
是這樣啊？
That's social networking
那就是社群網路
Networking
網路
Service
服務
Is that how it is?
是這樣啊？
I see now
原來如此
I'm so sorry
我感到十分抱歉
But
不過呢
what I'm about to tell you is the truth,
我接下來要跟你說的是事實
so I want you to take it seriously.
希望你能認真看待
I see.
知道了
Next week,
下個星期
I want you to come see my father.
希望你能跟我父親見面
What?
什麼？
Your father?
要我見你的父親？
What? Did you hear that?
什麼？你有聽到嗎？
Akitsu, did you hear that?
秋津，你有聽到剛才的話嗎？
Sure!
沒問題！
How about we stop marking messages as read and, instead,
拿掉已讀的標示
This could make waiting for the message to be read
如此一來，發出訊息的人 就能在對方看到之前
more enjoyable for the sender.
滿心期待地等
If five people haven't seen the message, there would be five hearts.
所以如果有五個人未讀 就會有五顆心啊
It adds a bit of fun.
讓人心跳加速耶
Right?
對吧？
This new feature would prevent people from feeling hurt.
這就是誰都不會受傷的全新功能
NAGISA INUSHIMA
（犬島渚傳送了照片）
It's gorgeous.
好奢華喔
This way.
這邊請
This is my father.
他是我父親
This is Mr. Ichiro Ogawa.
這位是小川市郎先生
Nice to meet you, sir.
很高興認識你，伯父
Are you all right, sir?
伯父，你怎麼了？
Sir, lift your head.
伯父，快把頭抬起來
Father.
爸
What? No.
什麼？不對啊
You're the father.
我才該這麼叫你吧
Who is this?
這是誰啊？
You're my father, aren't you?
是爸沒錯吧？
Sorry?
你說什麼？
if I become a champion, will you marry me?
若我成為霸主，你願意跟我結婚嗎？
Don't cut in, shoulder pads.
別來攪局，你這個墊肩的傢伙
We're connected with the field.
現場跟轉播連上了
Please show me the ropes!
請多關照
Is this allowed?
這樣做可以嗎？
That's a cover-up!
這是在隱瞞吧！
Father.
爸
Take care.
小心點喔
What are you doing, geezer?
老頭，你在做什麼？
What the hell have you done?
你這混帳幹了什麼好事？
Subtitle translation by: Ai Matsuoka
字幕翻譯：黃思為